Guide to the Cornell University Library Public Affairs records, 1957-2005.
Cornell University Library Public Affairs records, 1957-2005.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University Library Public Affairs records, 1957-2005.
13-1-1967
Cornell University Library Public Affairs
4 cubic ft.
Donor files and general office files.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Files on important donors to and benefactors of the library, 1957-1984; general office files, 1981-1987.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
In 1991, the Development Office became Library Public Affairs.
Adrienne McNair, Director of Development for the Cornell Libraries, and Kappa Alpha Fraternity organized a project in 1980 to sell stuffed bears in order to endow a new book fund at Cornell.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Files on important donors to and benefactors of the library, 1957-1984; general office files, 1981-1987.
Includes a bear wearing a shirt printed with "I'm a Bear for Books, Cornell." Also, a one page description of the fund raising project.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University. Library. Public Affairs.; McNair, Adrienne.; Cornell University. Library. Development Office.; Kappa Alpha Society. Cornell Chapter.
Subjects:
Fund raising.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Office files arerestricted to permission of office of origin.
CONTAINER LIST
- Adelmann, Howard (Box 1)
- Bird, Samuel B. (Box 1)
- Blinn & Cuthbert (Box 1)
- Caplan, Harry (Box 1)
- Catlin, George (Box 1)
- Cox, George H. (Box 1)
- Fries, Waldemar H. (Box 1)
- Given Foundation (Box 1)
- Haage, Aranka (Box 1)
- Halsey (Box 1)
- Hays, Robert L. and Lois M. (Box 1)
- Monroe, Benton S. (Box 1)
- Myers, Fleda S. (Box 1)
- Rosenzweig, Margaret (Box 1)
- Runsdorf, Herbert J.A. (Box 1)
- Ruzicka, Ivan J. and Jirina M. (Box 1)
- Sage, Henry (Box 1)
- Scheetz, Virginia (Box 1)
- Seager, Oscar (Box 1)
- Stratton, Marion (Box 2)
- Sullivan, Frank (Box 2)
- Tuvin, Julius H. (Box 2)
- Van Loon, Henry (Box 2)
- Whitney Straight Group (Box 2)
- Academic Assembly - Minutes (Box 3)
- Annual Report (Box 3)
- Association of Research Libraries (Box 3)
- Australian Government (Box 3)
- Bibliographies (Box 3)
- Annual Report documentation (Box 3)
- Book Plating 1985 (Box 3)
- Boyle Collection (Box 3)
- Canadian Government (Box 3)
- Cornell Fund 1986 (Box 3)
- Culpepper Foundation (Box 3)
- Campus Visits 1983-1986 (Box 3)
- Deposits 1987 (Box 3)
- Development Planning Group (Box 3)
- Development Staff Meeting Minutes (Box 3)
- Engineering (Box 3)
- Endowments (Box 3)
- Gannett Foundation 1985-1986 (Box 3)
- Gleameade, John N. Pew Trust 1985 (Box 3)
- ILR (Box 3)
- JGSM (Box 3)
- Judaica Collection 1981-1986 (Box 3)
- Law (Box 3)
- Legislative/Hearings and Updates (Box 3)
- Library Donor Associates 1986 (Box 3)
- Library Donor Statistics (Box 3)
- Library Gift Figures (Box 3)
- Library Advocates Council 1985-1986 (Box 3)
- Library Advocates Council Background (Box 3)
- Mann Library (Box 3)
- Melton, Andrew 1985 (Box 3)
- Osher, Bernard Foundation (Box 3)
- Purcell Weekend (Box 3)
- PA College Development Committee Meeting for Officers (Box 3)
- Reunion 1986 (Box 3)
- Tower Club 1986 (Box 3)
- Snow, John Ben Foundation (Box 3)
- Staff Review (Box 3)
- Agriculture and Life Sciences (Box 4)
- Automation Libraries (Box 4)
- Cornell Recognition Break (Box 4)
- Council University Library Minutes 1986- (Box 4)
- Dean Dinner, June 11, 1981 (Box 4)
- Dean Proposal (Box 4)
- Arthur Dean 1-4 (Box 4)
- Arthur Dean Book Contest (Box 4)
- Conservation 1982-1986 (Box 4)
- Inventory Control 1985 (Box 4)
- Foundations (Box 4)
- Funding-Foreign Services (Box 4)
- Fuertes Exhibit (Box 4)
- "New York" (Box 4)
- "CHICAGO" (Box 4)
- "PHILIDELPHIA" (Box 4)
- "NEW BRITAIN" (Box 4)
- Gifts in Kind 1985 (Box 4)
- Gift Policies (Box 4)
- Library Advisory Council Minutes (Box 4)
- Library Advisory Council 1-6 (Box 4)
- Math Library (Box 4)
- Mineka Gifts Memorial (Box 4)
- Music Library (Box 4)
- Metro New York File (Box 4)
- Program Directors Minutes 1985,1986, 1987 (Box 4)
- Records Conversion (Box 4)
- Special Gifts/Cornell (Box 4)
- Trustee Council Weekend (Box 4)
- Uris Library 1984- (Box 4)
- Vet School 1987- (Box 4)
- Viking Project (Box 4)
- Viking (Box 4)
  - CUL Cruise 1998 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Kovary (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Events 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Abby, Elfriede Gift 1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Bookplate Contest 1994 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Campus Visit 1994 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Campus Visit 1987 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Class of 1938 1993 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Class of 1944 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Colman Retirement 1995 1995 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Cook, Alice Papers (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Corson-New York City 1995 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Eissner Gift 1993 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Exhibitions 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Fuerst Awards 1999 1999 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Fuerst Awards 1998 1998 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Fuerst Awards 1997 1997 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Fuerst Awards 1996 1996 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Fuerst Awards 1995 1995 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Hill Gift 1995 and 1998 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Kroch Birthday 1994 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Kroch Library Dedictaion 1992 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Kroch Library Naming 1991 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Maeda Collection 1998 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - McCarthy Room Dedication 1994 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Newfield Birthday 1990 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Philadelphia 1993 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Rawson Room Dedication 1995 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Reunion 1995 1995 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Reunion 1994 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Reunion 1993 1993 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Reunion 1986 1986 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Robison Room (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Severinghaus Dedication 1 1992 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Severinghaus Dedication 2 1990 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Siew Nim Chee Banquet 1995 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Stern Dinner 1995 1995 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Students/Kids in Library (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - People- Staff 1994 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - A-F 1987 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Badgley, John 1993 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Dean, John 1994 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Dimunation, Mark 1993 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Engst, Elaine 1994 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - G-L 1994 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Gamelan 1991 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Irwin, Alice (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Kenney, Anne 1993 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Kroch, Carl 1935 1992 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Library Departments (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - M-R 1991 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - S-Z (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Van Tienhoven (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - White, A.D. (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - White, E.B. (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Seznac, Alain 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Student Workers (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Graphics 1992 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Dimunation, Mark-New York City 1994 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Library Holiday Cards 1980s-1996 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Library Holiday Cards 1997-2001 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Library Holiday Cards 2002, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Library Holiday Cards 2004, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Annual Report 2005 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Annual Report 2003-2004 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Annual Report 2001-2002; 2002-2003 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Annual Report 2000-2001 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Kroch Dedication 2002 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Kroch Brochure 1998 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Lavoisier Event 1995 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Dimunation, Mark-Talks 1994 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - CUL Campaign 1996 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Mann Campaign 1998 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Preservation Campaign 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - CUL Publications pre 1996 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - CUL Letterhead and Logo 2001 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Logos-Individual Libraries 1990s-2000 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - CUL-Institutional Identity Project 1996 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Images-Asia Collections (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Images-Audobon (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Images-Book of Kells (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Images-Children's Literature (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Images-City Planning (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Images-Civil War/Anti-Slavery (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Images-Division of Rare and Manuscript Collection (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Images, Publications-Echols (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Images-French Revolution (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Images-Fuertes (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Images-Hilda Sachs (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Images-History of Science Collections (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Images-Human Sexuality Collection (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Images-Icelandic (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Images-Illuminated Manuscripts (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Images-Johnson Family Papers (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Images-Judaica (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Images-Lavoisier (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Images-Nuremberg Chronicles (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Images-Preservation (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Images-Rare Collections (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Images-South Asia Collections (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Images-Willard Straight (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Images-Witchcraft (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Images-Wordsworth (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Images-Technology (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Images-Theater (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Images-Wason (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Images-Buildings-interior (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Images-Buildings-exterior (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Images-Engineering (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Images-Fine Arts and ILR Libraries (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Images-Kroch Library (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Images-Kroch Hirshland Gallery, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Images-Library Annex (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Images-Law Library (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Images-Mann Library (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Images-Mathematics Library (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Images-Music Library (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Images-Olin Library, Libe Cafe (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Images-Physical Sciences Library (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Images-Uris Library/Tower (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Images-Veterinary Science Library (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Images-General Library and Library Fellows (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - ACRL Award, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Slide Shows, 1981-1991 (Box 6, Folder 15)